yeah I I love this line at the end too
he says as a bonus you get to spend
another week after all of this figuring
out how to do regression testing so all
future deployments don't have it again
and no one accidentally re reintroduces
the bug if you're lucky you'll have
someone report that one Edge case later
that you forgot to consider and then
bundle it with a free consultation about
how an ASM product can solve this
problem for you
[Music]
[Applause]
hey guys real quick I just wanted to
tell you about our sponsor threat Locker
now wait wait before you hit the skip
forward button let me just say this most
of the stuff that holds my attention
nowadays is red team stuff as well but I
sat down with the threat Locker team
this past week to do a demo of their EDR
software and it was super technically
fascinating how this thing works so
check this out you drop this thing on a
system right and for the first week or
so it's creating a policy and a profile
for that system it's logging all the
executables uh what child processes are
being spawned uh the files and their
hashes that sort of thing and it's
creating this policy okay then after the
learning mode is up we're in secured
mode and that policy gets put into place
and anything that's not on that allow
list is immediately autod denied that's
the zero trust piece right so in
addition to that they've got a bunch of
crazy features like ring fencing and
dynamic access controls that would stop
a malicious hacker at pretty much every
step along the way actually I I was
watching this demo and I was kind of
freaked out because I have no idea how I
would cope with getting dropped into a
threat locker system as a red teamer
anyway if you want to learn more about
this head over to threat locker.com and
request a demo and when you do ask for
my boy Andrew his demo was super to the
point and he was able to answer all my
technical questions all right cool back
to the
show man if only the audience did the
blooper that we just had oh man that
blooper we're going to have to send that
one to the critical thinkers I think so
um anyway let let me get back to the
subject matter uh I'm prepping for this
Defcon talk right now and essentially it
is a summary of all of the crazy bugs
I've found within the past couple years
and dude that memory of me and you
popping that
router that was that was the best fan
that was such a fun bug I'm really
excited to see what you're able to
well what I maybe not what you're able
to but what you're going to say about
that yeah dude I have like this meme of
you and you know like I want to say it
was probably
when like man I think it was when hacker
one did like a like a photo shoot in
like the streets of uh New York back in
the day and you've got your like Hood up
and your GL glasses on and you just look
so badass there's a picture of Andre
from that same photo shoot we posed next
to like the same sign yeah oh really
yeah yeah somewhere there's a there's a
Xerox ACB photo as well I have to say
that that photo shoot that hacker one
did with y'all was like one of my like
core motivation features you know like I
I saw that and I was like I have to
become a live hacking event hacker like
it is my fate and voila here we are here
you are manifest indeed indeed man all
right so um we got a couple things hit
today before we talk about our primary
topic Which is less writing more hacking
essentially how to write reports quickly
and well for bug Bounty programs and
I've got a tool I'm going to release
with this so should be pretty fun
awesome yeah I I normally drop these
things first to the critical thinkers
but this one I was like you know what
I'm gonna I'm gonna just uh drop this
one for everyone this time yeah I saw
these links in the in the doc and I was
like these I is this like new what is
this yeah it is man I just got it PR
into the project but we talk about that
in a second um
news uh really cool thing happened this
uh this week I saw a a post um on
Twitter from the RC man and then I saw
Gareth Hayes comment on it with one or
with two chilling words nice research
exclamation point underrated reply
seriously and when Gareth you know when
that's coming from Gareth it's like okay
we done something right you know um and
this was uh the the Tweet regarding
essentially xss Waf bypasses by using
multi-ch character HTML entities and
from what I can tell there's just like a
bunch of entities that I didn't know
existed like the ersan and then you do
some you know asky string and then the
the semicolon and if it the that is
being interpreted by the server um and
in getting HTML decoded uh even if it's
like checking for less than or something
like that there are some some weird
attributes like um Ampersand
nvgt or Ampersand nvlt which will
convert into the less than and greater
than signs Plus some other uh Unicode
character um I thought this I never
heard of these by the way um and I don't
know if you saw there was actually a
second reply that Garrett sent to this
tweet as well which was a link to
chazzer which is a tool tool that we
talked about last week um and and well
actually the the initial reply is broken
but he followed up with with the new
fuzz on it but MH Gareth added uh a fuzz
to Shazer that tests for this
specifically and finds all of the ask or
URL encoded values um that'll work in
JavaScript URLs which is great so that
now you know like what things you can
put in there that will actually work and
bypass there yeah it seems really rad
and and essentially it looks like he
just kind of hit it with I'm not
actually sure where he's getting the the
source for all this but um there's a
bunch of different strings you can put
in between those the Amper sand and the
semicolon sign um and it's interesting
though because
that if you use the one that they
mentioned in the tweet it becomes a less
than and a string like a Unicode string
right so it's like uh I'm not sure if
this is actually going to because that's
not a valid tag right so yeah the the
less than one is a little bit like I
mean maybe it would work in those
scenarios where HTML like you're able to
trigger an xss using any HTML attribute
like there's some stuff in the ports
sger xss cheat sheets that's like uh you
know this this onclick Handler or
whatever will work with any element and
they always just use the xss element or
whatever um so it might work in that
scenario but the one that I'm more
excited about is the um ampersand
nvgt semicolon um entity and that one
will uh do the greater than sign which
will allow you to close off tags um
which could be really really helpful
that's awesome that's awesome yeah so
this is super super cool I love this
kind of research um I'm sure that there
are probably some
other instances of this as well um and
uh the the Shazer thing from Gareth is
actually specific typically for URLs so
um one example that he showed is that if
you do like an AA with JavaScript colon
one and hat semicolon alert one then
that will like work I guess um so that's
just like a a very interesting bypass
there's a lot of um these characters and
HTML encodings that seem to work so I
definitely recommend taking a look at
yeah that that one was kind of
interesting I I wasn't sure I'm not sure
about that one I I want to go and
actually check and see if that works CU
that doesn't make a lot of sense to me
that that it would work with that with
you're talking about the one with the
JavaScript URL yeah yeah yeah that one I
don't know about that one like I see
that he put that in there just to kind
of smuggle in the Jay character or
whatever but um I think that might only
be in some Niche scenarios where it cuts
off the first string but if it actually
does work that would be
nuts yeah yeah I don't know it's super
weird yeah so actually you know what
let's let's just check it out right now
hold on just let's let's just uh you
know do do the nerd snipe hey guys real
quick I just wanted to give a shout to
the hacker content team they have been
absolutely killing it the past couple
months taking the content from the
podcast and condensing it down into
consumable social media posts whether it
be shorts or text posts or whatever
they've been rocking it so uh I just
wanted to give them a shout out and let
you know that they do all sorts of cyber
security content as well as social media
management they do technical blogs they
do uh comprehensive social media
management uh so if your organization
could benefit from any of those types of
services make sure you head over to
hacker content.com drop them a line and
mention the podcast when you do to get
your first month of cyber security
content marketing services for free all
right that's it let's get back to the
Pod no way okay okay okay okay you can
you can that that was crazy okay that
does actually work hold up this is way
cooler than I thought it was so this
payload this payload like so you're
signing this to location.href um an
onclick Handler in an in an a tag right
and it's the it's Ampersand FJ
L
semicolon avas script alert one right
and but and that that character is
supposed to convert to FJ I thought when
HTML decoded and I was like so what is
that going to work like why is there an
F just in front of the JavaScript scheme
but for some reason this actually works
where where if you look at the actual
href back SL
FJ a v a s c r i PT just normal
JavaScript colon alert one it pops dude
mind absolutely blown super interesting
and yeah because back slf must get
converted to a special character I
wonder if there was like a yeah if you
had like a like a t as well like there's
a variety of different characters that
would fit that criteria that would
probably get ignored or something yeah
wow very interesting I guess yeah I
guess you're right I guess it gets
converted like back slf gets converted
to something that yeah gets converted
like the backs slash stays so it becomes
back slash FJ and then the J becomes
back slf JavaScript and then then backf
is like must be some special character
something that's getting ignored it
doesn't seem like it's anything special
but it must be
ignored because it's escaped or
something I know that there are
definitely cases like that like in Json
de code and stuff where backslashes get
ignored so it could be something similar
like that but yeah that's really
interesting so and because it's a
location it's like an on click on the a
ref so it's not it doesn't look like a
link but it's like clickable elements
That's crazy dude so I'm I'm looking at
this and I I I looked it up back slf is
a form feed character to indicate that a
printer should start a new page so it's
like like some Legacy printer version of
back sln which of course if you have
that before the JavaScript uh scheme it
does work very interesting well that
research is a lot more interesting than
I realized when I put it in this uh in
the podcast notes so if you haven't
already definitely go check out that
post by the rce man Anton um we'll link
it in the description below um wow kind
of mind blown at this point yeah super
cool super super cool
um all right uh let's go ahead and move
along I I'm still a little bit stunned
honestly that's really really
interesting let's let's go ahead and
move along to the next one though um
this was uh some research that came out
this week nextjs cash poisoning and you
can read through it and it's I mean
there's definitely a good technical
write up in here um but here are some of
the takeaways I had from this okay um
one I think cash poisoning might be the
new like subdomain takeover yeah yeah I
I I think like you know subdomain
takeover is super duper competitive
nowadays um
and the Recon boys so to speak are
having to Pivot into into different um
different attacks different attack
factors to you know spray across a mass
um scale and I think that the best way
that this might be one of the best ways
to make money through Mass automation at
this point is Mass scanning for cash
poisoning and I'm looking because I'm
looking at this write up this guy did
and he made a chunk I mean there there
are probably 20 something reports here
at least um that he associated with this
one bug all all paid out and accepted
and triaged um just from this one this
one thing so I think tax could be the
way to go yeah I mean so I think we're
definitely seeing sort of the pivot I
mean automation is always been like a
very fluid sort of thing where yeah um
it depends on like what's exploitable in
mass and what's what there's a lot of
and like where the competition is and
like how to get that edge and stuff and
so you've definitely seen like subdomain
takeovers sort of being starting to be
solved as a systemic problem where all
the providers who are vulnerable to
subdomain takeover are implementing
methods where like they're no longer
vulnerable to it because I think their
customers are complaining about it
reports and stuff so right like so um
you know because when you get a subeme
takeover for a third party product
you're going to reach out to that third
party and say hey like we have this
issue like how do we fix it right um so
you know it makes sense um but yeah
you're definitely seeing this shift
where now like subdomain takeovers are
starting to get harder and harder and
more competitive and it's like a super
fast race to claim it first and all that
kind of stuff so you know when you pivot
to a more complex vulnerability or
something that's a little more technical
you get that edge and you do much better
payout and I and I think the cash
poisoning the beauty of the cash
poisoning thing is it's something you
can validate pretty easily automatically
right like if I add this header does the
response drastically change you know um
I think that's pretty validatable um and
I know that there are a lot of people
doing cash poisoning at scale already
I've had some good conversations with
people um about that and building out
Automation and making quite a bit off of
it so um definitely definitely something
to look at uh there for anybody who's
big into the Recon space um other
takeaways I had from this was
uh just get the code base for whatever
you know technology you're trying to
look at and just grep for headers grep
for you know x x dash or whatever right
um and any mention of customized headers
Within These sort of Frameworks and
something like that uh there's there's a
lot of possibility I think that's a
really interesting attack surface that's
kind of that's kind of underestimated
because a lot of times we're looking for
you know parameters and trying to trade
the data as it flows through um qu
parameters or body parameters or
whatever Json blops but we're not
necessarily thinking about okay wait I
can also trace my input from Custom HTTP
headers um yeah so that that's
definitely another another attack
surface to keep your eye on um and then
the next one was I just love this quote
from this uh from this write up it says
quote the application was Cash poisoning
itself and so the devs added this cash
Buster and I think that's a really good
um a really good takeaway from this
right is let's if you see a cash Buster
anywhere the application was likely you
know cash poisoning itself and the dev
is like oh how do I fix this ah cash
Buster right you know and uh and so I
think that's always a good place to look
for those owner abilities well and it's
also like again pull down the source
code and look through some of that stuff
go back
one thing I love to do is if there's
something like a cash Buster for example
and you notice there's a cash Buster MH
it on GitHub click blame there's a
little button for it okay and and it's
it's a get blame it you know it's it's
sounds a little more mean than it is but
really what it is is it's a log of every
line in the code who committed that line
and and you can go and you can view the
commit so you can see okay the line that
added this cash Buster was from this
commit you go to that commit you see
what PR came from it was probably the
commit that went and fixed that original
cash poisoning now you go and you look
and see okay where was this affecting
where did they fix this how did they fix
this is there bypass yeah yeah or you
what I thought you were GNA say was you
run a G blame you find the developer
that that did that [__] and then you you
look at everything else that they've
ever written in that code base and be
like all right let's just pick on this
guy godamn Justin that's hilar
Justin's a Savage Justin's like I want I
want to take this person and and make
their life horrible you imagine want to
find every mistake they ever did if it's
like if you just did that to one
developer and and like you just submit
like 15 bugs and they're all from this
guy's code
pae that's so mean you're just like I
just noticed that John Smith committed
this yeah your your your AR enemy is
like you know a Dev on an open source
project or something like that like
tagging him on every issue you file yeah
you're going down um so speaking of
things at scale you saw this uh this
tweet from dagly right yeah dude okay so
that was kind of a weird situation I
want to get your take on this as an absc
guy okay so um ngly ngly tweeted out
this um uh nuclei template about how
exactly to scan for these this sort of
polyfill IO domain takeover that
occurred and it's crazy because I've
seen poly Phil
iio everywhere man and and essentially
the situation with this was that domain
got sold to bad people essentially and
now they have like a back door on every
website that's ever used polyfill.io um
which I feel like there needs to be some
sort of like regulation surrounding this
at the Domain level you know my American
is screaming right now saying pry dumb
blah blah blah but like man if you have
a domain that is so widely used in so
many ways there needs to be some sort of
transfer um system or surrounding that
applied at the at the Domain level
because uh man just transferring that
away to Rogue act actors gave a back
door into like a ton of
websites yeah yeah it's super super wild
um it's really interesting so well one
thing I was thinking about recently is
that there's a there's a new PCI
requirement um for anybody who deals
with PCI and stuff but um the one of the
PCI requirements is that there you have
to have change and tamper detection on
um payment and checkout pages and not in
the sense of like monitoring for code
changes but monitoring for dynamic
changes like scripts that are loaded
that are not um expected or that they
have change signature and stuff and I
think that's a very interesting call out
in retrospect on like this sort of of
vulnerability because if any company
that has that sort of monitoring would
probably have noticed this um so it's
just something you know very interesting
um that I was just thinking about the
connections between the two of those and
and you know how it would have played
out from sort of like an absc
perspective um but yeah as a whole I
mean these types of things are like very
difficult to find to detect like even
what I just like mentioned of like
monitoring for dynamic script execution
on a website that's a very difficult
thing to do like you basically have to
you know use like some headless browser
or something like that to you know load
the page and then somehow you have to
Hash it and like yeah you know it's a
very that's a pretty
interesting sort of business idea isn't
it like monitor the upcoming changes to
PCI compliance specs like I promise it
exists don't worry and and like say okay
oh they're gonna like make this
requirement for us to have this headless
browser that does change monitoring or
whatever here's your solu if you search
PCI 11.6.1 yeah you'll get there's like
at least five or six companies that are
doing exactly
that oh my gosh yeah look at that wow
crazy yeah well but I mean like in the
future it's kind of an interesting thing
like like I'm sure there will be changes
to the PCI spec in the future absolutely
um and I think that they goes through
like a review process first where and
that those reviews are public so as soon
as that gets released and there's a new
a new requirement in place that requires
some sort of technical solution getting
a head start on deving that deving that
deving that and reaching out to
organizations that are going to need it
I think that's a really uh a really
great business model yeah um yeah
absolutely anyway so it was interesting
to see that ngi released a a nuclei
template for that that definitely helps
I don't know that I mean and he's kind
of doing it related to Shockwave I don't
know that that would result in bounties
what what do you think about that Joel
yeah so I don't like just simply
pointing it out is one of those things
that I guess it depends on the program
like some programs will probably like
maybe as a thank you if they didn't know
or
something um I have a feeling it's
probably also maybe one of those things
where the platforms would like
potentially argue that it's like a zero
day or something like that I don't know
um I think it's definitely like a nice
thing to do but you probably shouldn't
expect a bounty like you know if you
have the automation set up like I can
see for somebody like Nagle that it's a
good business proposition to be like hey
not expecting a bounty just want to let
you know I have this software called
Shockwave it detected of you know this
vulnerable uh software on your website
you may want to fix that also if you
want to sign a contract here's my email
like you know and like do something like
that but um kind man he's on top of all
these things dude he he pinged me uh a
couple days before the Magento thing hit
hit the public and was like hey this is
gonna be crazy and he he's got a good a
good feed on that so he's got his finger
on the pulse yeah nice it's pretty good
for
Shockwave um what's this other thing you
got on here man okay yeah so okay so sha
yo uh you know friend of the fod um he
uh he tweeted out this amazing um blog
that he wrote I guess
um and it's uh it's titled um hey why
can't I get what was the title again hey
why can't you fix this one bug yeah hey
why can't you fix this one bug and it's
it basically Chronicles a researcher um
being like you know imagine your
security research you scan the internet
you find this endpoint on some company
you submit the bug hoping for you know
Easy easyy Money easy money and then
you're like why can't developer just
remove the route and it's a walkth
through of like the other side of the
conversation and it's such a great blog
um you know we've definitely had this
conversation uh a multiple different
times but I think this does a great way
of illustrating it in more depth on sort
of a generic level um of what it's like
being a security engineer and like the
process that you go through and the days
turn to weeks turn to you know whatever
um as you're just trying to like figure
out how to fix this and who owns it and
where it is and what the issue is and
meanwhile all the research it sees is
like Hey where's my bounty bro did you
just remove the rout like why can't you
just remove the route and the researcher
I think a lot of the time researchers
like they think that um every website is
just like a like a you know 30 lines of
flask code and like a python file and
they're just like what do you mean
there's like there's just you just like
highlight 15 lines of code you press
delete delete and then you save and you
rerun the python file like like what's
the big this shouldn't be this hard I
was reading through this and I was like
man this is absolutely me like I I am I
am uh I'm going through here and you
know every step along the way he's like
talking about all this like L7 load
balancing and like Lambda this and blahy
blahy blah that and I'm like I have no
idea what you're talking about like I
consider myself pretty like familiar
with uh I I guess application
architecture and stuff but like nah like
like I only know it from the outside man
I only know it from the outside and it
seems like this is a really interesting
read for me
because there's there's so much more to
it than I than I anticipated uh and you
know the the at at one point somewhere
in here he says like you know oh I I
figured out sort of roughly where it is
but wait I can't touch that I don't have
privileges to touch that and and can get
a Dev to touch it not a chance it's Q2
you know like nothing happens in Q2 and
I'm like what how does this what yeah
it's so real it's so real uh yeah so I
would recommend anybody who's just I'm
sure everybody's had this thought at one
point that's like why can't they just
remove this like what's like what's
taking so long whatever read read
through this blog post um it's a very
it's it's a short read it's very easy to
read uh it's a good read it'll
definitely put you in the mindset of
like what it's like to be a security
engineer and then I I would recommend
that anytime you're like what is taking
this team so long just pull this up read
through it and be like oh yeah that's
why yeah I I love this line at the end
too he says as a bonus you get to spend
another week after all of this figuring
out how to do regression testing so all
future deployments don't have it again
and no one accidentally re reintroduces
the bug if you're lucky you'll have
someone report that one Edge case later
that you forgot to consider and then
bundle it with a free consultation about
how an ASM product can solve this
problem for
you I did not even play that I didn't
read that that end part that's so funny
which is like which is like has nogly I
love how we put that right after our
segment on nogly
too wow that's amazing that's great
anyways this is this is a great blog
from Sean so go check it out uh on his
blog I think this is a new blog for him
um mu. PW
mwy um but yeah we we love Sean yeah
Sean is great dude yeah wow that's
that's hilarious man all right so let's
um let's get to the topic matter for
this week um and I guess I'm going to go
ahead and start with uh what's down
towards the bottom of the doc Joel which
is sure lately I've been thinking okay
um AI right how can it thinking AI
lately I've been
thinking Justin's just kind of sitting
there in the hot tub hm AI said
yesterday that if he had any ideas for
how to
do something related to the podcast he
should write it down and he's out here
thinking about AI instead no no I was
sitting in the hot tub thinking about AI
not those things um so as I was sitting
in the hot tub thinking hm AI like as I
do you know I'm thinking what are the
ways that this can apply to bug bounty
hunting and and hacking and there's a
lot of applications that kind of pop
into the brain um but what large
language models are best at is dealing
with with text and human parsible text
really um they do great work with with
code and stuff like that too but mainly
writing and generating text is is what
it's great at when do we have to
generate text in the bug Bounty
flow for the report at the worst part
I'm not dude I'm not gonna lie I
literally like writing reports
is it pushes me over the edge sometimes
like I will literally I'll find
something and I'll be like is it really
worth my time to write this report no is
it worth writing the report well see
even if I find something critical I'll
be like now I have to write this up okay
so I do not have that if it's a critical
if it's a critical I'm normally like
super hyped to write their report I'm
like let me show him how I like did this
and I like bypass that and like you know
like that's what that's what's happening
in my brain was like a little snapshot
said just for a
second um
but yeah and uh and so but what I don't
love writing is those stupid like
reflected xss reports I'm like okay
here's a quick little reflected xss like
obviously you can just grab the token
and get you know account take over or
whatever so it's like it's not a big
there's not like this whole like
technical thing normally if there's some
cool flow where I like do this OA thing
and like grab the code and get atto then
it's it feels a little bit more
fulfilling but when it's like super
basic it it it's just really annoying so
so let's start with that right like the
first the first tip and the thing that I
always like and I know you have
something for this is report templates
right I I know hacker one has this
natively yeah I assume bug crowd on the
other platforms probably do to some
extent if not just keep a folder on your
on your computer and probably put it on
GitHub
which Q Justin yes oh talking about this
repo
yeah which um yeah so so listen so
listen here's the thing about the report
templating thing okay
um I do have a repo github.com
rreps that is essentially a report
templating software that I used back in
the day when I was doing a bunch of
automation stuff and I was just
submitting the same bones over and over
and over again sub takeover blah blah
blah then you know take the domain run a
dig dot or jig plus trace on it take the
output put it in the report that sort of
thing right and it's written in Python
2.7 it's not very long um I didn't even
because I'm well listen I'm not going to
roast you it's okay it's old dude here's
the thing though like I started writing
python when I was 12 you know and and I
around that same time was when they made
the transition Python 3 yeah right
people don't realize like how well both
how old and how young python is like
yeah yeah and and I at that point you
know I was I was a young I was a young
guy and I was like I kind of got my my
head into the Python 2.7 ecosystem I was
more of a programmer at that point than
I was a hacker I was just Lov to progr
pramming with python and um and I was
very against the python I mean there was
a whole sort of resistance movement
against python too man like it I was
like you mean I got to put parentheses
around my print so infuriating like why
would you make that that change like
it's ridiculous in hindsight though I
was like yeah that was such an outlier
like why why why wasn't their friend we
don't need that all we need is our
youthful rage Joel at at at the system
um anyway so I held off on switch to
Python 3 for years and then I finally
have and you know now I'm thinking okay
now I need to learn how to write rust or
go or whatever so that's going to be on
my what did you say the other day that I
didn't know the H2 or uh H2 yeah
yesterday I was like it's it's the start
of H2 and you were like what's H2 and I
was like it's the second half of the
year it's like corporate speak man I
don't know that I I barely know what
quarter are we in right now
three three just started thank you um so
anyway
that's on my 2025 H
H1 there we go uh goals learning to R
rust or go one of the two but um okay
let me just finish this segment Jo yeah
sorry I I'm derailing you really hard no
you're good um so essentially we have
this uh github.com
rreps repo it's written in Python 2.7
literally just handed to chat gbt and
convert it to Python 3 I did get the
chance to do it before this episode it's
very simple all it does is just takes
your mark markdown parses out the
templates allows you to run uh to
provide like variables into the
templates and also run commands on the
command line so you can automatically
insert stuff like um you know dig
commands and then the output from the
Dig commands into the report super
helpful um that really helps but here's
what I was going to say before which was
I have a tool now to write the reports
using AI so essentially what what it
does is um it uses this really cool
framework called fabric from um Daniel
misler okay and uh I I actually in the
doc I've got my own Fork of it listed
listed here but it actually got merged
into main um yesterday so um essentially
what fabric is is it's a way the way he
describes it is it's a way to augment
humans with AI essentially it's it's a
framework around collecting prompts or
they call patterns in this specific
environment and um allowing you to very
easily send data to that via standard in
typically and um and get uh the results
passed to AI so you can you can pass it
to chat GPT you can pass it to uh Claude
you can pass it to your own olama server
there's lots of uh cool stuff that's
built into there you can have it have
context um about you as a person Lama by
the way so oh is there really don't
expose don't don't expose your Alama to
the network but oh really I make sure
it's up to dat but yeah there was there
was just a CB inama Rec I think that's
really I think AMA would be a really
interesting um thing to go after because
they've got like role-based permissions
and stuff like that too you can have
like users and admins and that sort of
thing um but I wrote this pattern called
Write _ hacker oneor report and
essentially what it does is you can
provide it with an input that contains
requests responses and then
comments um and it will take that and
can take into consideration your
comments look at the request and the
response and write a report for you
based off of that um that fits the
hacker one sort of model right you've
got like the summary the details the
steps to reproduce and the impact and
like you know various supporting
resources and that sort of thing um and
so in order to get everything in the
right format for all that I wrote this
other tool called BB bug Bounty report
formatter that's on github.com rator BB
report formatter um and essentially what
that does is it allows you to just very
easily send in requests send in
responses send in comments and it'll
store them in your on your local system
and then whenever you tell it to you can
just do use-- print D report and it will
dump out the um report structure and
then you can just pipe that right into
um fabric uh WR hacker one report and it
will uh generate the ai ai based report
now here's the question question I know
you're you're it's in your head Joel
okay might be in your head might not be
in your head does it actually freaking
work and the answer to that the other
thing that's met in my head well okay
doesn't work well we we'll finish I'll
let you finish I'll let you finish the
answer to that is sort
of oh no so it works really well with uh
chpt uh 40 or four whatever yeah the new
one yeah the new one it gets great
results it I gave it a v that I had from
before that's already closed and uh it
wrote an awesome report for it easy
peasy I just gave it the request the
response and some description of the vul
and it took it away okay but the goal
with this whole thing was to be able to
do this with private AI to be able to do
it with AMA on my local system so that
it doesn't leak the
yeah so that it doesn't like leak the
the um report contents yeah to open Ai
and that does not work quite as well uh
it works pretty poorly actually um so I
don't know I think I think it's an
interesting Ed Case I'm still going to
release the tool because some people
will use it with chat GPT and that's
fine
um I I'm definitely looking forward to
to seeing progress in private AI uh
because this really highlighted for me
the difference between a A system that
like like jpt stuff and something like
AMA using like uh llama 3 or llama 2
model right I mean the results were just
drastically different yeah yeah super
interesting um one thing I I did want to
mention and this is completely this is
like the totally wrong takeaway I'm so
sorry okay you said come on what is
going on today man okay I'm just sorry
said that um to convert python 2 to
Python 3 you should just throw go what
are you talking about okay there's a
built-in tool okay if you don't know
this there's a built-in tool in Python
it's called two to three number two two
number two word two number three two to
three and it converts python 2 scripts
to Python 3 no it does not it does
that's what it did search it up two to
three anyways just I'm just leaving that
there
it exists wow check that out it's pretty
cool all right like version 3.13 or
something but like if you haven't
converted your python stuff at by now
you what cool yes I was gonna be mad at
you but that's actually really cool yes
for that is like the one case where I'll
say you don't needed to use chat GPT for
this uh you can use something much uh
less AI that will probably not get it uh
start hallucinating halfway through your
script yeah no that that that makes
sense
um very cool someone someone should do
that maybe I'll do it afterwards maybe
I'll do it before this podcast airs who
knows I got a lot of stuff on my on my
on my plate this upcoming week but it
would be it would be interesting the the
the takeaway there though is is really
worthwhile to have some sort of
templating system in place and I I just
kind of use the hacker one templates and
um use some of the AI stuff that I've
I've built in now but um I think you
know before when I had this more
advanced templating system especially if
you're reporting very similar bugs time
and time and time again um yeah it it's
very helpful and I recently had a
scenario where I I had to report 25 very
very similar bugs and I used report
templating and it just saved so much
freaking time yeah I will say like if
you're not doing full-time bug Banny
um like and you don't like need to be
like submitting like a lot of reports
like in in Mass like that like or if
it's not something you've like farmed
like if you're report submitting 25 the
same report template is a great solution
for that but if you're not a full-time
bug Bounty Hunter I don't think
necessarily that like trying to shortcut
the whole report writing process is a
great idea per se like I think it is
kind of like I mean to some extent right
so like say you're not like a native
English speaker and you're like I want
to make sure like this is readable I
think that's a good use case for like I
know for example hacker one has like
rewrite with Hai thing or whatever um
you could maybe do that with chat GPT or
maybe AMA just to rewrite it and to make
it more readable but like having it
generate and like write the report
itself at the end of the day you're
going to have to reread through it to
make sure that it's actually right and
that it actually got everything correct
and if you're doing that then you're
like halfway there pretty much to just
writing the thing yourself I don't know
I feel like it is kind of part of the
process I don't know I think it depends
on what it is um like the should be sort
of a line I think where like it makes
sense to have the AI be writing a report
for you versus just writing it yourself
um because like at what point do you
like need the AI to write like how much
time is it saving you to
like collect all this stuff put it into
the AI read through what it writes
format that like what you know it's like
again you're like probably 50% of the
way they it helps man it helps and it
does help I I think I think for me like
just seeing the way that it it worked
for my sample stuff that I wrote
associated with this I literally like
took one request one response one two
sentence you know thing about how how to
access this thing and it extrapolated a
bunch of the correct details it's like
what type of um bug was it it was an
idor it was an idor and there was
another one for reflected xss worked
great um and that's pretty
straightforward though right yeah yeah
no absolutely yeah and that's the that's
the use case where where right now I
just don't feel like writing up these
super annoying bugs you know and I just
like okay just send it off all you have
to do is just tell the triager like log
into the application go get this ID from
here and and then do this do that and it
it actually did a really good job this
is the part that was surprising to me um
the application that I was I gave it the
test data from it it knew about that
application it's a pretty popular
application and it was like oh you know
this is the functionality in this
application um you can get log in go to
this spot and then and then do this
thing and I was like oh wow that's like
I didn't tell you about that you just
kind of knew that kind of weird kind of
funy you know like yeah so so it I'm
sure there will be problems with it but
I think for me having to actually get
out of my hacker brain and into my
writer brain and and start doing that I
think that will be um I think this will
be a big a big timesaver for me so I've
only used it you know a couple times but
um I think I think it'll be helpful yeah
right it's like yeah for sure I agree
with I think like it depends on the use
case and like if you find that use case
for yourself where like it makes sense
and like it's something simple like that
um or it's just like a big time saer
where you know there you don't have a
template that fits it nicely or whatever
you can't just like copy paste the
company name and it's not something in
mass and it needs to be a little more
custom and like AI is great for that or
like having something rewrite it for you
with just like a little bit of info is
great for that yeah yeah I agree and I I
wanted to shout out while we're while
we're at this segment I wanted to talk a
little bit more about fabric as well
because um fabric is is pretty rad there
there's a couple other patterns that
that I use pretty regularly that that
come in here as well the create command
one in particular is great so you can
just say like Echo uh write me a uh
command to you know a said command to
like remove this or that or the other
thing and just pipe that into fabric
create command and it will write that
whole command for you and I'm like like
pipe it together and stuff yeah yeah and
get built out and and uh it knows I mean
you can give it more context too you can
give it more like the Man pages or
whatever and that sort of thing and it
and it will be able to tie stuff
together um but for Stuff where you're
constantly trying to like uh what was
that syntax or whatever um I think this
is really I think this is really handy
um and the other ones so there's clean
text which I think is a really
interesting one you can kind of tell it
give it some text and it will try to
pull out like all of these weird
formatting things and try to get it in a
very consistent format and I think this
is something that you know we've all
become pretty Adept with using like said
grep a you know all these things to try
to get the text in the right format um
but for the beginner that is just trying
to get stuff to be in the right format
for like an intruder list or something
like that um I think this could be this
could be really helpful H dude you know
I'm really conflicted about this whole
thing because this this reminds me of
the conversation that we had with with
was it um yeah with Keith
about like the Google effect of this on
memory and learning where it's like I I
do think it's worthwhile to like know
how to use said or know how to use ABS
or know how to like use these
fundamental Linux commands to modify and
chain data and not just be like let me
ask the AI how to do this and just have
like copy blindly copy pasting it's like
the equivalent of like you know stack
overflow or whatever like just like you
know copy pasting code Snippets and just
not really knowing what you're doing and
I think like this is something like I I
absolutely I want like things to be
easier for people but I also don't want
to encourage like the wrong type of
learning and behavior around this where
like this should be something that you
should be learning or using like as a
utility to make your life easier not to
like do something you don't know how to
do yeah NE necessarily like and there's
like a line right where like you know
something's not worth your time and then
okay you shouldn't be wasting your time
like learning this but like learning how
to use said
like again like I think like the
fundamental Linux knowledge and stuff
that you're going to gain off off that
is like so much more valuable and more
applicable than like for ex for example
using it to write a report like you
don't need to like go learn how to like
write like a PhD student in order to
write a report right you can just have
like the AI do that for you but you
should learn what the Linux commands
that you're
there's a limit to that right like we
all have limits to our knowledge I know
how to use said and a and cut and all
these things very very fluently but I
don't know all of these super abstract
edge cases for JQ or like you know some
of these other applications right but
imagine if you did yeah but I yeah but I
don't you know and I've got other things
to do besides like especially when
you're HCK this is a really important
takeaway I think especially when you're
hacking you want to try to remove as
much friction as possible to you being
able to get to your goal in the hacking
scenario right so for things like this
yes it's helpful to have that knowledge
about said and a and if you want to take
the time to learn that outside of being
in the zone from a hacking perspective
then that's great but at the end of the
day when you're hacking you need to
stain your flow and you need to remove
as much friction as possible so that's
where I think stuff like Fabric and
integrating these clean uh clean text or
create command um patterns could be
really helpful because it removes that
that I got look at the docs blah blah
blah and now I can just okay here's what
I need to write copy paste it and go
yeah your cat's tail is like right in
front of this I was I I was gonna say
yeah um I think
uh you know there is right there's like
a line I forgot what I was gonna say now
um I remember yeah yeah so like
definitely I would recommend setting
aside some time to be able to learn
these things right like don't always
just say that like oh in the in the
effort of like going fast and like not
getting out of flow I'm not going to
bother learning this thing and then
you'll like never learn it um I do think
it's important to like set aside some
time for yourself to learn these types
of things so if it's something that you
don't want to learn now but you think
that you should learn later put it in
like a a note file or something and then
like set aside like one day a week or
something if you're a full-time hacker
or a couple hours per week or or certain
times of a day where you can go and can
research those things and not feel the
pressure to um be hacking but instead be
learning to improve your hacking and and
hone it you know yeah what what I
recommend to my mentees as well is doing
that sort of supplemental learning
during times when you can't deep focus
on hacking so let's say you've got an
hour at this Cafe while your kids at
their swim lesson or whatever right take
that hour and instead of trying to like
get into a Target and in an hour and
like find a bug which you could you know
it's possible especially if you you
structure your time properly um but but
instead of that maybe take some time go
learn all these commands go learn about
go set up some environment that's going
to save you some time and reduce your
friction when you do have Focus time
like four hours or something like that
where you can really be in the in the
zone um that's that's sort of my
recommendation yeah I also love doing
that when I'm in um constrained
environments like on a plane on a train
um traveling in an Uber like when you're
in constrained environments and you're
just like what do I do instead of
scrolling Twitter go find an article and
read through that article because you're
much more likely to actually read
through it and occupy yourself than you
are to like do that when you're at your
computer and you have a million other
things that you can be doing yeah and it
doesn't make a difference just that one
time but if you get in the habit of
doing it like and you keep on getting in
this habit of like ah let me read this
article instead of scrolling Twitter let
me like uh figure out how to use this
this Linux command while I'm you know
waiting in line at the grocery store or
something like that then that knowledge
will compound compound compound and
you're just going to be Mega leite at
the end you're going to be the next Tom
Nom Nom absolutely absolutely yeah so
all right well I guess on the on the
note of like taking some time biting the
bullet and setting some stuff up I do
have a couple recommendations um uh in
addition to what what we've mentioned
here already
um I always record a a PC video that's
that's the first one like unless it's
literally click the link see the popup
and even then if it's going to be a
bounty above like 500 bucks or something
like that I'm gonna if it's a bounty
that I'm going to be upset to lose if if
like the end point goes down or
something like that I'm always going to
record a PC video because it's so it
takes so little time it it shows proof
that the thing happened and uh it just
makes it easier for these Tri aers that
are skimming reports more and more
nowadays um so one that's one tip always
record a PC video and two remove
friction to recording that P video on
yourself um and make it a nice setup you
know uh what I'm using nowadays is OBS
and I've sort of uh I really like the
way Loom has their setup in place right
and I wish I could use Loom but it it it
sends the video out to loom
automatically right which is kind of
like kind of meh
um so I I kind of set up my OBS to mimic
Loom and I've got like a little circle
of my face down at the bottom and I've
got you know the screen
recording on there and for some reason
my default setting on OBS I don't know
if you have this as well Joel but it was
it didn't have a pause button by default
it was like something about the way that
it's encoded i' got to check my OBS now
go go check it because um it didn't have
a pause button and I was like why why
does this not have a pause button
because it's super helpful when you're
recording a video to be like okay now
I'm going to Brute Force this for 20
seconds be right back and you just you
know press the pause button and then you
come back when it's you know done uh
brute forcing and then you can show the
result or whatever um yeah do you have
it no I don't I don't I don't think so
unless I have to start recording but
yeah that that's yeah I think you might
have to start recording with the like
start recording button down at the at
the bottom um before it pop up but I
don't know if because your your camera
and microphone are in use right now I
don't know if it can do it oh yeah I'm
not gonna I'm not gonna don't don't mess
with it don't don't mess with it um but
here if you don't have a record button
here's the way to get a record but
record button on uh not a record button
what if I say saying uh a pause button
on your recordings for OBS um go to
settings go to Output go good recording
and then change your recording um
encoder to
x264 and change the output type to MP4
and then save it um and and if you just
Google it there's an article on it you
know of course I just am telling you
from the article uh but essentially that
will give you the pause button just with
something with the way it does encoding
you can't pause with the normal encoding
and then that pause button will pop up
and you can easily pause unpause and
you've got a nice little setup and the
triager can see you and it makes a
connection and it's very easy to follow
so that that that's my tip there is like
go ahead and set that up and then reduce
as much you know set the auto output
directory to be somewhere where you know
exactly where it is and just reduce the
friction as much as possible to doing
these PC videos and then just uh just do
it every time and have a voiceover as
well talk to them through it say okay
now we're going over here we're clicking
this button then the attacker is like
you know doing this thing and just talk
them through the whole flow it will
really help to understand the full
attack vector and it will get your
reports to triage faster and it will um
even in scenarios I've actually had
triers be like hey I can't reproduce
this because of XYZ but I see you have a
video and I followed the video so I'm
going to triage this and and this just
saves you that extra time bump you know
yeah one thing I will say about the
video so if you can't in embed your
video in your report like don't I I
wouldn't because like for real because
making whether it's the program whether
it's the triage or whoever have to
download your mov file and like run it
on their like that should give everyone
an Nick and that's yeah please don't EMB
it yeah embed it in your report don't
just attach it as a thing on the end and
be like attached is a video record like
that literally just feels like a malware
email that you've sent me like please
see the attached PDF file and run it on
your computer like bro the report is
like uh the report is like um ability to
social engineer security analyst
into
right the the video prove of concept you
just opened this like hang on a second I
think I've seen this one before yeah
yeah but but but I mean I can't imagine
anybody doesn't know this but on on on
hacker Juan in bug crowd you can embed
the the videos directly in the report so
that you have to do that and and not
only that at least on hacker one there's
a built-in screen recorder so you don't
use OBS you don't have a screen recorder
set up there's a button you can click in
the hacker one web page like record my
screen or whatever you can record your
screen it automatically embeds it right
in the thing I don't know how well works
I've never used it before a little fun
and um you know just you know give it a
shot if you don't like it then you can
go through the effort of setting up OBS
or some recording software Loom is super
easy like you said like Loom is great
puts your face there puts your mouse
there uh it's very user friendly so yeah
there's definitely a lot of options yeah
Loom I've been using a lot recently um
for sending messages to you sending
messages to the other members of our
staff and then yeah Jessica communicates
to me with videos He he'll he'll be like
hey man are you around I'm like yeah and
then he'll just reply with like a video
[__]
like very true very true Joel's like hey
man what's your favorite color and I
just said respond to the loom link like
it's like hey so as you can see I'm a
pretty big fan of this shade of red
right here uh but also this one's pretty
good as
well oh my gosh yeah um but so
let dang it we are silly today Joel um
so regarding Loom I I did I did want to
definitely add this though that one it's
very helpful for sending like
collaborating with other hackers you can
be like hey check out this request it
literally you just press the record
button you record it gets your gets your
mic gets your you know little face down
in the in the corner it's recording your
screen follows your mouse all all those
sort of things and then literally the
instant you press stop recording it
generates a link then you can just drop
that link in a Discord chat or or
whatever and it will and your buddy can
like follow along with you exactly um so
that's super helpful for for um
collaboration and here's what I've been
doing with it recently that's been kind
of a game Cher is when I've got a step
away from work um for the night or
whatever and I'm in my zone and I'm like
man I wish I didn't have to leave I'm
like in my zone um just recording a loom
video to myself and saying hey um you
think this request I always I always do
it in the in the second person like you
think the currently you think that this
is really yell at yourself yeah this is
really weird and we should come back to
this request and um so yeah that's been
really helpful and then I'll just kind
of bookmark it and like put it right in
in an annoying spot in my bookmark bar
so I I see it as soon as I open up my
browser and uh and I watch that video
and that helps me drop right back into
the flow state that I was in the last
time that I was hacking um so that's
that's a big that's a big one man that
one really helps yeah yeah and I I love
that I mean that in combination with
what Braun said he does and I do this as
well where you try and leave yourself on
like a cliffhanger night before so that
you're really energized to go hack that
the next day um you know that's always
good to sort of set yourself up for
Success the next day and and have
something to look at and have something
to focus on instead of just sitting down
and being like hm what do I what should
I right that momentum is like super
important so keeping the momentum going
like across over throughout the evening
by sending notes to yourself and keeping
keeping notes of what you were working
on and where you were in that momentum
head Space is really really important
yeah yeah I I agree man I agree yeah
that that was such a great a great tip
from fron like I I had such an extreme
response to that I was like no that's
the moment that you got to like that's
that's when you that's when you Crush
the app into the ground that's what you
have to and no it's it makes a lot of
sense you just leave it you leave it is
you let let your brain sort of uh
reflect on it for the rest of the night
or whatever and then the next morning
when you need to get up at you know 5 AM
to go hack before your kids wake up you
you wake up and your eyes are like this
you know your eyes are kind of squinty
and then you know they just go wide open
and you remember and like let's go yeah
I gotta go Hack That Thing
exactly very real stuff there very real
stuff some people like their coffee in
the morning I like my yeah my last night
realization Joel what the freak
dude okay okay couple more couple more
reporting tips and then we're just gonna
wrap the stuff at the end otherwise
might weird people out poor listeners
this week man yeah so if this is your
first episode of critical thinking that
you're listening to I'm so sorry this is
not how we normally are um okay so
couple more tips dude I only just found
out I've been writing reports on hacker
one for seven years at this point I just
found out recently that you can use
syntax highlighting in your markdown
blobs yeah recently maybe like being
like two years ago or something this
isn't just a hacker one thing by the way
this is a thing yeah yeah yeah um back
tick back tick back tick and then
whatever language right so there's one
for HTTP Javas for like everything yeah
dude that is amazing there it's amazing
and my one of my favorite ones is HTTP
yeah um which is a a much less
well-known one but it basically is great
for highlighting HTTP requests the
headers and the body and that kind of
stuff um it works especially well on
hacker one I think they have some extra
stuff added to it that makes it work
nicer than it does in other places but
you can use this on Discord as well if
you're chatting with on and you send
them a BL a code block instead of just
some block of text what the language
there some color to it it's nice stop
itain it's like get some help
please it's like a paint by numbers you
know you can do it oh my God all you
have to do is just add the
language okay all right all right um
yeah okay let me ask you this do you
always so just read the whole markdown
situation do you always forget how to do
a linkoln markdown or is that like not
it's now burned into my brain I don't
know I just know I just know that it's I
don't know what my problem is with that
but I like always get it mixed
up so
um here's a here's a good way to think
about it if you were to send someone if
you were to write someone like right hey
here's this really interesting thing
what you would normally do is you would
put in parentheses after that the link
right okay right be like hey here's this
thing parenthesis like
right so it's the same in markdown you
just surround it and you just telling it
what it's square brackets and then
parentheses adding the context sort of
like that sort of thing yeah yeah the
link is like parentheses hit and the
square brackets are like link this thing
okay could you say that all again but
with a little ASMR like okay so the
first parth whisper the oh my gosh okay
all right now that's that's burned into
my brain now that is help though I think
having that parenthesis around the
towards the end I think that that is
that makes a lot of sense okay dude we
got to wrap this episode because we're
getting too luy um the last one the last
let me just let me just finish this out
okay um how many times can I derail Jus
in this episode no dude no it's not just
you man it's I gotta get a counter going
I got to get a world record yeah um so
last one that I wanted to to say was
screenshots are also very important in
writing your reports um you should be
including those on a really regular
basis and um
um a lot I know a lot of you are just
using like the built-in uh you know
Windows screenshotter whatever and or
some like jeny Linux one um I would
recommend not doing that even though I
did that for a very long time and still
sometimes do it because of muscle memory
and instead get something like greenshot
where it's very simple like you just you
activate with a key binding just like
you do with you know the windows
screenshotter you can select very
granularly you know it allows you to
select down to the pixel it's got a
little magnifying thing that says okay
from this pixel you know you drag your
your size for the screenshot and then
you can pop it up into like a little
screenshot editor where you can really
easily like draw arrows and add text and
stuff like that and and you're not like
trying to draw and paint like do this
super Jank looking Circle and like this
arrow that you drew with your mouse
cursor and um if you're on Windows the
best screenshot tool that I can ever
recommend is called share x what share X
why don't you put these things in the
dock
dude I gota keep these things these are
top these are top secret oh wow this
looks awesome top secret tips Shar X
yeah I think it's Windows only
unfortunately because it uses a lot of
c.net stuff um I've tried to cross
compile it from Mac before because I
like that much wow um but yeah sharex is
really really awesome um it you know
allows you to add blur arrows uh
rectangles um all all sorts of really
cool things it has like bounding boxes
and stuff it just copies to your
clipboard you can do custom upload stuff
so like if you have an if you want to
just like send it to some API endpoint
if you have a custom image uploader you
can do that yeah you can do that um you
know you can just have it copy to your
clipboard which is I what I usually do
yeah um but yeah sharex is really
awesome that's what I use on Windows for
screenshots on Mac I just use the
built-in screenshot thing um preview is
kind of okay but if you want to add
blurs and arrows what I use is called
Skitch uh SK Ki T C SK interesting
Skitch um let's add add that to the I'll
add it right now it looks like this
software may or may not
exist anymore uh oh did they did it like
discontinue or something like
that does it have like a little I can
find oh I can find like the CNet
download links hold on I I just put it
in the I just put it in the section in
the doc did you is that the one it's got
like a little arrow that is the one yeah
that's it I don't know how you found
that you know that's it hacker skills
man Google Google dorker skit yeah this
one's pretty good oh yeah it's made by
Evernote yeah oh is it really oh yeah
yeah yeah yeah that that's one of the
reasons I like it so it's made by like
pretty reputable company so Evernote
makes this yeah thisor called Skitch um
and you can have blurs you can add uh
little arrows to it um I think you could
probably do it in preview just the back
preview app as well but uh it's blurs I
don't know about that um but yeah um
share X on
Windows okay so that's your
recommendation my recommendation is
greenshot I'm gonna I'm gonna go ahead
because you didn't tell me about this
before the episode Joel and I didn't get
the chance to go and download it and
install it and provide my official
recommendation but we can leave that up
to the listener greenshot versus what
was the one for what windows that you
recommended sharex share X okay cool
yeah we'll see which one of those gets
the better uh gets the better review
from the Community um all right dude is
that a wrap I think we're done right I
think that I think that's a wrap all
right dude good luck writing your
reports everybody get this go go get it
guys all right peace
[Music]
peace okay yeah so after playing around
with it a little bit Joel's
screenshotting tool share X is way
better so ignore me don't use greenshot
use share X it's open source it's
amazing you're welcome